The world.
What a glorious place.
Seek freedom, and it will lie
stretched out before your eyes.
If the endless dream guides
your restless spirit,
seize it, raise your flag, and stand tall.
I think back to the time
when my search first began.
I left behind those shores of sand.
For the endless everlasting
world out there.
I know that with this
burning passion driving me.
Someday, somewhere, I'll finally see the
light I have searched for everywhere?.
When the summer sun is shining.
Shaking the sails of my heart. I know.
A brand new world
that has been hiding.
Has opened up its doors for me to go.
Wearing in the troubled waves.
From all despair I can be saved.
For the horizon on the other side is.
And though I've traveled far
from where my search began.
Over seas of green and shores of sand.
Through the endless
everlasting world I bear.
I know that with this
burning passion driving me.
Some days I'm where I'll finally see
the light I will search for everywhere?
I can't believe our luck.
Seriously, that orangutan almost sunk us.
And now it's up to me to fix it
all and keep this thing afloat.
Seems to me that this busted
old ship is on our last leg.
We need a new one.
How dare you even consider
replacing this boat?
Yeah, how dare you?
We all know the story, Usopp.
And try not to be so defensive.
The going mare is an
important part of our crew,
and we all know we have
to take care of her.
You shouldn't take
everything so personally.
You're right.
I'm sorry.
Oops.
We left Mocktown and
headed east by circling
around the northern shore of the island.
Our destination is here.
We're supposed to meet that man there.
What's his name?
His name is Mockblot Cricket.
And you're sure that he'll be
able to help us out, right?
Whoa! Amazing!
That's where he lives?
It's a freaking palace!
I've never seen a house that big before!
This Mont Blanc cricket
guy must be really loaded!
Look closer.
It's really unattractive.
A guy's got to have some serious
guts to build a house that ugly.
What's that?
This isn't a palace at all! What?
The actual house is only half that size.
What you see is a facade, a fake.
This guy's even more vain than I thought.
Why exactly did Cricket decide to
leave his home and come live here?
I don't know all the details,
but I think it has something
to do with his belief.
that a large amount of gold rests
somewhere in the hills of Jaya.
Gold?
Do you think he's here searching
for some sort of buried treasure?
Well, I just don't know.
Go!
Try over here, Chopper.
Take out this spot.
I'll be right there, Nami.
Must be hard to live alone
in such a remote area.
Hello!
Don't just barge in there!
Huh, looks like nobody's home.
Anybody here?
I guess he's gone.
Get out of there, you idiot.
This guy could be dangerous.
Hey, you guys.
Nobody's home.
Huh, what's this?
A book?
And it looks pretty old.
Huh.
It's called Nolan the Liar.
Sounds like it could be good.
I sure like the title.
Nolan the Liar? Yeah.
Have you heard of it?
It says here it was originally
published in the North Blue Territory.
It was.
I was born in the North Blue Territory.
I'm certain I must have
told you guys that.
No?
That's news to me.
I always thought you
were born in the East.
I grew up there.
Enough already, Chopper.
What are you doing?
Where I come from, this is a famous story.
It's a fairy tale supposedly
based on the life of Noland,
who lived in the North
Blue a long time ago.
This is a story of ancient origins.
The events herein transpired
more than 400 years ago.
There once was a man by the
name of Montblanc Noland,
who lived in the North Blue countryside.
Noland, who was an explorer,
always regaled the crowds with
stories of his incredible exploits,
but nobody knew whether or not to
take Noland's tall tales seriously.
One day, upon returning
from yet another adventure,
he reported to his king
all that he had seen.
I saw a city of gold on an island
in the Great Sea, declared Noland,
and the courageous king decided that he
must have this treasure for his kingdom.
The king set out with Noland and 2,000
of his finest soldiers. Along the way,
they endured treacherous storms and
battled many ferocious sea creatures.
At the end of their journey,
only the king, Noland,
and 100 soldiers survived to set foot on
the island that housed the City of Gold.
And all they found for
their troubles was a
normal island covered
with an ordinary jungle.
And so upon their return,
Noland was sentenced to death for
the crime of lying to his king.
His last words were as
follows I can only assume
that the city of gold
sunk into the sea the
king and his court were
dumbfounded nobody believed
in Oland anymore and the
last of his days were
spent in shame and ridicule
before his sentence
of death was carried out
before a cheering crowd
it says here that the
book is based on the true
Maud Blanc Cricket is an ascendant
of the infamous Maud Blanc Nolan!
I heard that fairy tale
all the time as a kid,
but I never knew that Jaya was the island
where he thought he saw the City of Gold.
When we were growing up in the North Blue,
we were always warned that if we lied,
we'd suffer the same fate
as Nolan and be ridiculed?
until we were eventually put to death.
It makes perfect sense that
Cricket's related to that fool.
But I can't believe that Jaya is
the island from the fairy tale.
Pardon the intrusion, but
if I heard you correctly,
you're saying a descendant
of Nolan is here
400 years after the fact
looking for that gold?
He's got to be doing
this to clear his family
name and regain some
small amount of respect.
This story keeps getting
better and better.
Can he seriously hope to
wipe away over 400 years of
embarrassment by bringing
back a few pieces of gold?
What a joke!
Sounds like he's a few
bricks short of a wall!
Alas, the liar died before he
could prove himself to the people.
All he ever really wanted to do
was live the life of an adventurer.
That last part's not in the book!
Don't try to tack on your
own sentimental nonsense.
Did he just fall in the water?
What's going on?
Who the hell are you?
You've got nerve relaxing at
someone's house without permission?
This is my land and I suggest you leave!
Hurry Usopp, move it, go and
fish Luffy out of the sea!
I know why you're here,
you're after my goal.
Don't worry, this guy's a terrible shot.
Hey, cut it out!
Idiot, never underestimate your bow.
Out of the way, I'll handle this!
You really need to learn
to be more careful.
But I thought I saw bubbles in the water.
So I looked closer, and
then a chestnut appeared.
But it wasn't a chestnut.
It was a guy, and he pulled me in.
What's with him?
I need more cold towels.
And open up those windows.
What's caisson disease?
So this guy is really sick, huh?
Yeah, caisson disease is an illness
that sometimes affects divers.
Though it's called a disease, it
isn't actually a chronic condition.
It's caused by a lack of decompression
when surfacing from the seabed.
The nitrogen in the blood
releases too quickly and
causes gas bubbles to form
in the circulatory system.
And when those gas bubbles expand,
they can cause considerable
damage to muscles
and joints and seriously
decrease blood flow.
So it's a mystery disease.
Think you can help him?
I'm not sure.
My guess is he kept diving every day without
allowing time for his body to recover,
and it finally caught up with him.
That's why he passed out during the fight.
But why in the world did he do that?
I don't know, but he
was taking a big risk.
In some cases, caisson disease can
cause death, so he's lucky to be alive.
Oh, hey, Mashida, I guess
you're still alive after all.
Why do you say that? Forget about it.
Do you know what all that
gunfire was about earlier?
I'm not sure, but that's where
I'm headed now to find out.
Well, come on then.
I'm worried about the old-timer.
Hey, old-timer, are you all right?
They've come to kill us!
What in the world are
you people doing here?
And just what are you
doing to our friends?
We're trying to help,
so I suggest you either lend us a
hand or find someone else to buy it.
Don't antagonize them, Luffy!
You know what they're capable of!
And now there's two of
those savages to deal with!
They're savages!
Everyone jump out the
windows and run away!
Thank you, guys!
What did they say?
So you guys live on this island, too?
Yep,
this old-timer's house is the official
headquarters of the
Saruyama Alliance of Jaya.
We call this home, but we spend
most of our time on our ships!
We're more comfortable at sea, because
this place is too small for us.
You guys are too big for your own good.
But it's all in how you
look at it, I guess.
To a giant, you'd still look like
nothing more than a ball of earwax.
Well, those three sure are getting
along well now, aren't they?
Yeah, seems like they
have a lot in common.
I'm pretty impressed you managed
to get Machida here off your ship.
It's quite a feat for someone as
small as you to overpower him.
Eh, it wasn't really that hard.
What's that?
I'm sure you could kick his ass.
Wolf, he's waking up. He's awake?
Yeah!
He's right!
I can't kick Masi's ass!
Hey, chestnut head, I
got a question for you.
I'm sorry I attacked you.
I thought you were
nothing more than another
group of bandits who had
come to steal my gold.
Did someone say something about gold?
Just calm down, Nami.
What exactly was it you wanted to ask me?
We're searching for Sky Island,
and we were told you might be
able to tell us how to get there.
Are you serious?
Don't tell me you really
believe that place exists!
Stop it!
You can't attack a sick man!
You mean there's no Sky Island?
Are you sure?
I don't know.
See, nobody knows if the Sky
Island really exists or not.
I know of only one man who claims
to have seen the island for himself,
but he's considered a
liar of epic proportions.
What are you looking at?
There's an old fairy tale that the
people of the North Blue know very well.
It's called Nolan the Liar.
Stop looking at me, Luffy!
My name's not Nolan! Is he right?
And is this island the one
mentioned in the fairy tale?
Yeah, Nolan's my grandfather's
grandfather's grandfather.
He's a distant ancestor of mine.
I am his descendant.
But we're so far removed,
I doubt there's even a single
drop of his blood in my veins.
The Mont Blanc family was driven out of
the North Blue Country a long time ago,
and we've managed to keep a
very low profile ever since.
People still denounce the family name,
but we've never despised him for this!
But why?
Because Nolan, contrary to popular
belief, was a very honest person.
That's not what the fairy tale said.
As the story goes, Nolan's
last words were as follows.
I can only assume that the
City of Gold sunk into the sea.
This line is accompanied by an
idiotic face in the illustration.
But Noland was no idiot.
He knew what he saw, and I
believe he wasn't lying about it.
Noland was sure the island
he stumbled upon where he
found the ruins of a city of
gold was the island of Jaya.
But when he returned with
the king, there was no gold.
Unsuccessful,
he insisted that the ancient city had
submerged due to shifts in the Earth's crust.
But everyone dismissed this as the
last-ditch excuse of a doomed man.
Noland was given a public execution.
When he died, so did his discoveries.
Only the legend of the Liar remained.
I get it!
You're trying to find the Ancient City
of Gold at the bottom of the sea in
order to finally clear the Mont Blanc
family name and prove Noland right!
Don't be ridiculous!
I don't really care if the Ancient
City of Gold exists or not.
The actions of my ancestor have
nothing to do with me and my life.
You can't possibly begin
to imagine what it's like?
As a kid for everyone to
laugh at you and ridicule
you because you're a
descendant of that idiot.
Noland.
That's what I've dealt with my whole life.
Anyway,
over the past 400 years,
a great many of my family have
set sail to find the city of gold,
prove Noland right, and
restore the Mont Blanc name.
But each and every one
of them went missing.
I was ashamed to be a member
of such a pathetic family.
So I decided to leave home
and become a pirate. Wow!
So you're a pirate just like us?
I didn't even really
want to become a pirate.
I just wanted out of Nolan's
shadow to be my own man.
But over time, I came to
assemble my own pirate crew.
Finally, I was seen as a leader,
not a laughingstock, and I spanned
the world looking for adventures.
Then 10 years ago, So as my
crew and I sailed the calm sea,
we discovered this
island purely by chance!
And ironically,
of all my family members who sought out
this place, who lost their lives doing so,
it was I who found it!
I who despised the Mont Blanc name!
We came ashore, but found no
trace of the City of Gold.
I stood on a cape of the island and
felt I was destined to be there!
Let's settle this,
Noland, once and for all!
You're on your own!
We don't want anything to do with this.
We're setting sail and leaving.
If you want to stay here and
search for gold that doesn't exist,
you're doing it alone.
So long, Captain.
I don't care if I find the city or not.
I'm not here to prove
Nolan right or wrong.
I have no interest in rewriting history.
All I'm doing is following
what I believe is my destiny.
This is between me and Nolan.
I'm facing what I fear, and whatever the
outcome, the act is all that matters.
Wow, what a sad story.
But what about the monkeys?
How did they come to be on
this island with you anyway?
I'm sure that's another story of
bravery in the face of incredible odds.
Your life reads like a great
book, you know, Cricket?
They were just fans of the fairy tale.
They're fans?
How did they find you?
I think it was five or six years ago.
They heard a rumor and set out to find me.
Those two truly believe that the
City of Gold exists somewhere,
and they're helping me find it.
Shoujo, you have no idea what
you just got yourself into!
Bring it on, you big ape!
I'm ready when you are!
Just step up and you'll get knocked down!
The sea surrounding this island
is very deep, and in those dark,
cold depths, you're surrounded
by a profound sense of solitude.
When I first arrived here, I spent
my time searching the seabed alone.
They entered my life
without permission and
assigned themselves as
my crew without asking!
And they do nothing
but fight all the time.
But having these idiots
around puts me at ease.
And truthfully, I enjoy their company?
You understand?
I understand completely.
True friends lift each other up and give
each other strength in times of need!
Are you just about finished
telling us your life story?
Shut your mouth, you ungrateful brat!
Stop it!
Look, all I really want to
know about is Sky Island!
You're a pushy guy, aren't you?
But like I told you earlier,
the only person who's ever
seen the Sky Island is Noland,
and nobody knows if he was telling the
truth or if it was just another tall tale.
Is there any record of
his trip to the island?
Officially, no, but he
does mention it in here.
What do you have there?
That isn't Nolan's logbook, is it?
Yeah, it is.
Read from the bottom of that page.
Amazing!
This logbook is over 400 years old.
June City, year 1120, a sunny
day on the Sea of Ephemeris.
Upon departing from the Jolly Villa,
we left the harbor and sailed
into the rising sun at a
heading of east by northeast
with the wind at our back.
At midday, we happened to cross
a bumboat carrying a rare item.
A single-person contraption
called a sky waver. This small,
mysterious vessel can
generate its own wind
and sail at great speeds
even on a still day.
But the ski-like ship was
not easily maneuvered.
I couldn't control it, although my
crew has taken quite a liking to it.
I gotta get one of those things!
Keep going!
Don't stop reading!
Uh,
we were told the vessel had been
manufactured on the Sky Island
and that many more interesting
devices could be found there.
It brought to mind an
explorer friend of mine
who once showed me the
most unusual specimen,
a living skyfish.
I have never seen a fish with such a
bizarre appearance in all my years!
This island remains the only unexplored
domain and as a sailor and adventurer.
I feel it is my destiny to one
day reach the sea in the sky.
Mont Blanc Noland.
Do you know what this means?
The sky island must really exist!
Just like Robin said it did!
Now we just got to figure
out how to get there!
You're up.
You feel it?
All right?
Better than ever?
Glad to hear it.
Shut up.
I need to ask you something.
What do you think of those guys?
Why ask an old timer?
It seems that they're
determined to get to Sky Island.
No matter what.
Sky Island.
You know?
There's only one way
for them to get there.
And if they try to get there
on their own, they'll die.
Exactly.
I think we should help them along.
So what do you guys think about that?